# Robert Bishop

## Full Stack Engineer

□ rbishop2006@gmail.com

www.robertbishopdev.com

**\** 804.869.2541

♦ Las Vegas, NV

in /in/robert-bishop-3837b61

rbishop2006

"The keys to my success have been communication and time management skills along with a drive to learn new technologies. I am experienced with working on deadlines, collaborating with team members, and target goals that need to be achieved. I have learned new technologies at the request of my supervisors and I am dedicated to developing great looking websites that function efficiently and intuitively."

## Technologies & Skills

#### FRONT-END

React

TypeScript

Material-UI

Semantic-UI

Ant-Design

CSS3

SASS

HTML5

JavaScript ES6

### BACK-END

Node.JS Express.JS

Koa.JS

MySQL

TablePlus

#### **VERSION CONTROL**

BitBucket GitHub

#### ORGANIZATION

JIRA

### DOCUMENTATION

Confluence

Notion

## API

Algolia

Twilio - SendGrid

#### **TESTING**

Jest

React Testing Library

## Work History

Full Stack Engineer · HealCo, Inc · 03/2021 to Present www.healco.us

Remote (NJ/NY based company)

- Constructed highly reusable and extendable React wrapper components around the stock Ant Design framework to accelerate and facilitate development.
- Created components ranging from standard content to secure portal HIPAA-compliant content using modern authentication techniques.
- Completed full stack projects using our React Custom Hooks and functions utilizing Koa.JS and MySQL for all of our RESTful network requests.
- Improved security around the HealCo mailing list signup component on our landing page.
- Learned and used TypeScript in the front and back end code of our application. Updated legacy code and created new components to be type-safe utilizing TypeScript.
- Researched unit and integration testing frameworks and integrated Jest into the HealCo project to improve the quality of the development workflow.
- Leveraged multi-disciplinary past career experience to contribute valuable input on solving roadblocks in our site's UX while offering advice on our online ad strategy that improved our conversion rate.
- Worked closely with and learned from others as a part of a lightweight engineering team that relied on stellar communication, collaboration and time-management.
- Followed a task-based milestone system that expected everyone to contribute their best work with integrity and passion.

React JS Engineer · TruLocal, Inc · 09/2020 to 01/2021

Remote (CA Bay Area based company)

www.trulocal.com

- Leveraged Algolia on the search route and created a responsive UI based on Figma designs.
- Utilized Chrome Developer Tools and modern CSS3 FlexBox and Grid to quickly assemble beautiful layouts on all screen sizes.
- Communicated with the design team and offered suggestions on functionality options available for integration into the components.
- Used Material-UI React components including cypress tagging in the elements while working directly with QA to ensure a smooth continuous integration process.
- Implemented Algolia's SearchContext and Algolia's React connected widgets to provide the desired search results and filtering options.
- Educated teammates on the best implementation strategy of the search results in their tasks.
- Participated in daily stand-ups and weekly sprints led by the VP of Software Engineering / Project Manager with the development team in an Agile environment.

Business Development - Sr Banker · Technology Credit Union · Spring/2014 to Winter/2019

San Jose CA - Remote Las Vegas, NV

- Ensured a smooth process for our customers by collaborating with our dealer contacts, TechCU's banking staff, and the Underwriting Department.
- Piloted a new remote role at the Credit Union that required cooperation with IT, the Executive Team, the AVP and VP of the Contact Center in order to make the project a success.

## Portfolio & Projects

**VetHead Brand** 

06/2020 to 07/2020

• VetHead Brand is a website that I collaborated with a partner to create a React application that utilized the Shopify SDK to provide the checkout functionality and client data for the store. The site was fully functional, able to process orders and is responsive at desktop down to mobile screens.

Jurn(ease)

03/2020 to 04/2020

• Capstone project for the PunchCode curriculum that is a full-stack application (React-Redux, SASS, Semantic-UI, Node.js, Express, MySQL) called Jurn(ease). It is a vacation planning site aimed at making the planning process cooperative between groups of travelers and relieving the stress of that process.

#### Portfolio

• Please view some of my projects on my portfolio site robertbishopdev.com

## Education

PunchCode · 01/2020 to 04/2020

• Fully immersive, fast-paced, in-person bootcamp where I worked on a development team to create functional and beautiful full stack applications with responsive design for web and mobile.

 $\textbf{Virginia Commonwealth University} \cdot \textbf{Fall/1998 to Spring/2003}$ 

B.A. Philosophy